Jesse Carmine

www.jessecarmine.com www.linkedin.com/in/jesse-carmine carminej@gmail.com

WEB DEVELOPER

Passionate front-end developer with 6+ years professional experience in designing and building responsive web applications that are elegant, intuitive, and accessible; seeking to obtain a position that will allow me to continue building the next generation of web apps using React.

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Tools/Software: React, Redux, Jest, Jasmine, Karma, Enzyme, Webpack, Gulp, Sass, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, Django, Git, GitHub, CircleCl, Docker, JIRA, Optimizely, BigCommerce, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, ArcGIS

EXPERIENCE

RevUp Software Portland, OR October 2018 – November 2019 Senior UI Engineer

- Built the front-end for RevUp's Nonprofit product from the ground up utilizing React, Redux, Immutable.js, Enzyme/Jest, and Webpack.
- Collaborated with UX Designer and Management to design a data-rich SaaS application that was elegant, intuitive, and performant.
- Planned projects, managed sprints, and delivered on several key initiatives.
- Mentored junior developers with a focus on building confidence, encouraging leadership, and advocating for exceptional code quality.
- Managed an external vendor in the development of various features of our application.

Gazelle San Diego, California September 2015 – April 2018 Front End Engineer II (Remote from Portland, OR)

- Led development on a reCommerce site that did \$3.5 million in sales per month.
- Retrofitted a Ruby on Rails app to replace legacy, unstructured JavaScript with React.
- Implemented Webpack to automate the build process and enable the use of ES6, React, and css-modules.
- Utilized Enzyme and Jasmine to add testing for new and existing JavaScript.
- Increased engagement and conversion rate through A/B testing, utilizing Optimizely.

Stride Rite Shoes Boston, Massachusetts April 2015 – August 2016 Front End Developer (Fixed-term contract)

- Managed and updated a major eCommerce website built on Demandware.
- Developed interactive features for desktop and mobile using JavaScript and ¡Query.
- Re-designed/developed the site to improve the UX for mobile users.
- Worked with designers, developers, and site-managers to rebrand the website for 2015.

Jesse Carmine carminej@gmail.com

BBK Worldwide Boston, Massachusetts January 2015 – March 2015 *Front End Developer (Fixed-term contract)*

- Developed desktop versions of websites from provided PSDs.
- Designed and developed, in consultation with the UX Designer and business, the mobile versions for each using the original comps as a guide.
- Collaborated with their creative team to improve the UX on mobile devices.

Hill Holliday Boston, Massachusetts October 2013 – July 2014 Front End Developer (Fixed-term contract)

- Developed websites, microsites, emails, and graphics for eCommerce applications.
- Sliced up Photoshop comps and built them out using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript/jQuery.
- Developed responsive layouts using media queries, responsive grids, and JavaScript.
- Managed projects using Git, GitHub, and JIRA.

University of Alaska Anchorage, Alaska March 2013 – September 2013 Front End Developer (Fixed-term contract)

- Worked to develop a Rails based data portal that catalogs and distributes scientific data.
- Assisted in designing the UI, produced wireframes, and developed prototypes.
- Developed the front-end using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, and Liquid(Shopify).
- Carried out cross-browser compliance testing to ensure full compatibility with IE8.
- Created GIS maps using existing data and completed analyses using ArcGIS Desktop.

Watershed Sciences, Inc. Corvallis, Oregon August 2008 – October 2011 Remote Sensing Field Technician

- Planned field surveys and collected airborne, remotely sensed data.
- Analyzed LiDAR data and digital orthophotos using ArcGIS Desktop.
- Extracted land feature information for use in conservation planning and GIS applications.

Applegate Forestry, LLC Corvallis, Oregon July 2007 – April 2008 *Technical Advisor*

- Provided natural resources advice to The Confederated Tribes of Warm Springs.
- Carried out field surveys to assess the current ecological health of their lands.
- Created GIS maps using collected data and completed analyses using ArcGIS Desktop.
- Conducted historical research to assess past land management practices.

EDUCATION
Oregon State University
Bachelor of Science, Natural Resources
Graduation Date:

Corvallis, Oregon

2007